Joshua Ogle

Product Designer and Developer

http://joshuaogle.com joshua@joshuaogle.com

Summary

User Interface Designer with a background in both graphic design and development. Interested in delivering beautiful user experiences through simple design, brilliant ideas and seamless interaction.

Specialties: User Interface / User Experience design, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby, Design & Illustration

Experience

Product Designer at Citrusbyte

September 2016 - Present

While at Citrusbyte, I have filled an important role mentoring other designers to build their skills, from standardizing user research practices to starting regular critique and helping to hire all of the new designers. It has been a very rewarding experience to develop official design practices and improve our team while still doing client work for large influential companies.

•

Designer at thoughtbot

March 2014 - August 2016 (2 years 6 months)

Designers at thoughtbot have a very wide range of responsibilities and every one is one of those "unicorns" you always hear about. Responsibilities include design fields such as Design Research, User Testing, Branding, User Interface Design. On top of that, designers develop the front-end architecture with HTML5, Sass and Javascript libraries like Angular and Ember. Our open source tools like Bourbon and FormKeep help designers worldwide easily build their sites with cutting-edge tools for the modern web.

Co-founder and Director of Design at Brightbit

February 2011 - March 2014 (3 years 2 months)

Co-founder and lead designer developing web apps for internal projects and client work. We took a team of three people freelancing in the evenings and grew it to a consultancy employing 7 people full time. I was responsible for Creative Direction for all of our projects and lead Front-End Development.

Interactive Designer & Developer at The Oklahoman

April 2009 - February 2011 (1 year 11 months)

User Interface designer and front end developer working on wimgo.com, the largest collection of events, restaurants and community information in Oklahoma while will launch nationally in Summer 2010. As a senior designer/developer, I helped audit the existing code to prepare for a national launch and ensure best practices. I also lead design and development of wimgo's Business Resource Center which is one of the primary revenue sources for the site.

Web Designer at Element Fusion

October 2008 - April 2009 (7 months)

Worked with clients and project managers from project planning to design to development and integration

with ElementFusion's proprietary LightCMS. After many years of working in customer service roles for other companies, I loved working directly with clients and helping small businesses gain a presence on the internet with beautiful designs. I only left to focus on interface design and get experience working on a large development team.

Education

University of Central Oklahoma

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Graphic Art, 2001 - 2006

University of Oklahoma

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Painting, 2000 - 2001